# Julio Cesar Hernández García

## Resumé - Julio Cesar Hernández García

#### Resume

## Objetive

Seeking a position as a System Administrator and a productive team member with a progressive company that provides opportunity for career growth and job satisfaction.

#### Skills

Strong communication and organizational skills, creativity, flexibility, reliability, a talent for team working, high emotional intelligence, social competencies and strong motivation for professional achievement, self-knowledge, and ability to handle conflict. Excellent abilities with web applications, Networks, software and hardware operation and maintenance

Strong knowledge and experience with Linux, Unix and Windows.

Strong knowledge of Internet Technologies such as TCP/IP,VoIP,Ssh,Smtp DNS, Proxy, FTP, Webmail, Proxy servers, Reverse-proxy servers, Load Balancing, HTTP, LDAP.

Experience supporting and deploying highly scalable applications written in PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, C++, Perl, Python

Solid knowledge and experience of web servers such as Apache, Nginx, Cherokee and lighttpd

Experience with automation and monitoring tools such as Puppet, Nagios, SNMP, Kick-

### Education

2008-2012 Management Specialist Science and Technology, University Rafael Belloso Chacin.

2002–2008 **Computer Engineer**, *University Valle del Momboy*.

Urb. Campo Alegre, Calle la Arboleda Casa Nº37, Carvajal, Edo. Trujillo, Venezuela

♠ +58 (426) 279 9921
♠ ☎ +58 (271) 2444854 ☑ jhernandezgar@gmail.com • 🕆 www.julioh.com.ve

# Additional Training

- 2010 **English Instrumental**, *University Valle del Momboy*, 48 Hours, made between 01/06 y 30/07/2010.
- 2010 Cisco Networking Academy: Routing Protocols and Concepts, *University Valle del Momboy*, 60 Hours, made between 01/03 y 30/06/2010.
- 2010 Cisco Networking Academy: Networking Fundamentals, *University Valle del Momboy*, 60 Hours, made between 04/01 y 19/02/2010.
- 2008 **UML Design Workshop**, *Biosoft C.A.*, 32 Hours, made between 30/08 y 03/08/2008.
- 2007 **Introduction to the Exploration and Production**, *Schulmberger*, 16 Hours, made between 01/07 y 02/07/2007.
- 2006 **Wireless Telecommunications**, *Cantv*, 60 Hours, made between 02/05 y 02/07/2006.
- 2006 **Certified in Open Source**, *University Valle del Momboy*, 192 Hours, made between 02/05 y 02/07/2006.
- 2003 **Component of English Academic**, *University Valle del Momboy VEN-USA*, 253 Hours, made between 01/04 y 14/10/2003.
- 2003 **Equipment Repair and Maintenance**, *University Valle del Momboy*, 8 Hours, made between el 11/04/2003.

# Work Experience

- 2011-2012 **Systems Analyst and Programmer**, *IUTEMBI Instituto Universitario de Tec*nología Mario Briceño Iragorry, Development of the website, as well as virtual classroom management and other subsystems have.
- 2009-2011 **Systems and Platform Manager**, *University Valle del Momboy*, Software Development, Server and Network Management.
- 2007-2009 **Analyst and Technical Support**, *Petróleos de Venezuela S.A* . Development and testing of software modules, on-site Technical Support
- 2006-2007 **Thesis**, *C.V.G. Electrificación del Caroní C.A.* .

  Design and specifications Proprietary Platform Migration towards Free Software, SCADA at the substations of CVG Electrification of the Caroni, CA
  - 2006 **Intern**, *C.V.G. Electrificación del Caroní C.A.*.

    Web Development (PHP,MySQL), modules for providers, staff and Induction Guide Plant Division Caruachi.
- 2004-2006 **Scholar in Computer Lab**, *University Valle del Momboy*.

  Maintenance, Support, Networking, Administration Servers (Proxy, DNS, WEB, Mail, FTP) in Centos Linux.

# Presentation at Conferences and Meetings

- 2010 **Speaker**, FLISOL(Latin American Festival of Free Software), SITrujillo, UNESR, Fundacite Trujillo, Servers LAMP(Linux, Apache, Mysql, Php). Valera, Trujillo Venezuela
- 2010 **Workshop Facilitator**, *X Congress ExpocTecnologia*, University Valle del Momboy, *Servers LAMP(Linux,Apache,Mysql,Php.* Valera,Trujillo - Venezuela
- 2007 **Speaker**, 3th National Congress of Free Software-Trujillo, GNU/Linux Organizado en Venezuela, CMS: under free software.

  Valera, Trujillo Venezuela
- 2007 **Speaker**, 3th National Congress of Free Software-Monagas, GNU/Linux Organizado en Venezuela, SCADA's: under free software.

  Maturin, Monagas Venezuela
- 2007 **Speaker**, 3th National Congress of Free Software-Sucre, GNU/Linux Organizado en Venezuela, SCADA's: under free software.

  Cumana.Sucre Venezuela
- 2007 **Speaker**, *3er Congreso Nacional de Software Libre-Anzoategui*, GNU/Linux Organizado en Venezuela, *SCADA's: Bajo Software Libre*.

  Puerto la Cruz, Anzoategui Venezuela
- 2007 **Speaker**, *III International Workshop on Free Software*, Informatica 2007, *CMS:* under free software.

  La Habana Cuba
- 2006 **Speaker**, *IV World Forum on Free Knowledge*, SOLVE(Software Libre Venezuela), *CMS: under free software*.

  Maturin, Monagas Venezuela
- 2006 Speaker, Day of Free Software Installation, University Valle del Momboy, How to Install Linux on Your Computer?.
  Valera, Trujillo - Venezuela

#### **Events and Tutorials**

- 2007 **Assistant**, Event, Informatica 2007, XII Convention and International Expo. La Habana Cuba
- 2007 **Assistant**, *Event*, University Centroccidental Lisandro Alvarado, *University Conference on Free Software*.
  - Lara Venezuelaerú
- 2006 **Assistant**, *Event*, University Valle del Momboy, *VI Congress Expotecnologia*. Trujillo Venezuela
- 2005 Assistant, Event, SOLVE(Venezuela Free Software), 3th World Forum on Free Knowledge.
  Zulia Venezuela
- Urb. Campo Alegre, Calle la Arboleda Casa №37, Carvajal, Edo. Trujillo, Venezuela 3101

- 2005 **Assistant**, Event, UNPLUG(Linux User Group), 1fs National Congress of Free Software.
  - Trujillo Venezuela
- 2005 **Assistant**, *Event*, University Valle del Momboy, *System Audit*. Trujillo Venezuela
- 2004 **Assistant**, *Event*, University Valle del Momboy, *IV Congress Expotecnologia*. Trujillo Venezuela
- Assistant, Event, University Valle del Momboy, VI Conference on Sustainable Human Development.
   Trujillo Venezuela
- 2003 **Assistant**, *Event*, University Valle del Momboy, *III Congress Expotecnologia*. Trujillo Venezuela
- 2002 **Assistant**, *Event*, Gerenplanif, *I Binational Conference*. Merida Venezuela
- Assistant, Event, University Valle del Momboy, V Conference on Sustainable Human Development.
   Trujillo Venezuela
- Assistant, Event, University Valle del Momboy, I Technology Days in Municipal Management.
   Trujillo Venezuela
- 2002 **Assistant**, *Event*, University Centroccidental Lisandro Alvarado, *XI Conferenc Science and Technology*.

  Lara Venezuela

## Knowledge

Operating Gnu/Linux(Debian, Ubuntu, Centos, Suse, Fedora, Red

System Hat), Windows, BSD, UNIX

Admintration Web, Proxy, DNS,FTP,Mail.

Office Microsoft Office (Word, Power- Hardware Assembly Equipment Fault Diagno-

Point, Excel, Access) y OpenOffice. sis, Computer Preventive Mainte-

nance.

Structured Java, J2ME, ASP.NET, Visual Utilities Eclipse, Geany, Vim, Nano, Gedit,

OpenMP) y COBOL.

Scientific Basic Matlab. Layout Layou

Program

A.I.

Programming CLIPS, Scheme, Prolog. Scripting Bash Scripting, C-Shell, PHP Avan-

zado.

Web Design HTML, XML, XSLT, XQuery, Database MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle,

XPath, CSS. SQLserver.

Languages

Spanish Native

English Average